Guide to the Houston Arts and Media Oral Histories, 2006-2007 MS 524
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Houston Arts and Media Oral Histories
2006-2007
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Houston Arts and Media (Houston, Tex.).
MS 524
1 Linear Feet (1 box)
4.42 Gigabytes
A collection of compact discs containing interviews with members of various Houston, TX communities, documenting their memories of the old neighborhoods. Interviews conducted by members of Houston Arts and Media for the organization's Neighbor to Neighbor project. At this time the recordings have not been transcribed.
Historical Note
The Houston Arts and Media group has the mission statement of collecting and presenting educational and historical information in the form of films, videos and books. In June 2006, Houston Arts and Media began interviewing members of various Houston communities on their memories of the old neighborhoods. The interviewees came from all walks of life and a wide variety of neighborhoods all around Houston and its associated counties. Houston Arts and Media titled this project Neighbor to Neighbor.
Scope and Contents
A collection of compact discs contains interviews with a wide variety of individuals from various neighborhoods around Houston, TX as part of Houston Arts and Media's Neighbor to Neighbor project. These interviews were conducted in order to compile a collection of oral histories regarding historical neighborhood life around Houston. This collection contains both an MP3 version of the interview, as well as a CDA formatted version. In total, Houston Arts and Media donated about 50 hours of interview digital recordings. At this time these recordings have not been transcribed.
Access Restrictions
This material is open for research.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored on-site at the Woodson Research Center.
Acquisition Information
Donated by Houston Arts and Media April 4, 2007
Index Terms
Subjects
Transportation; Education
Document Types
oral histories (document genres)
Places
Texas -- Houston
- Series I: Interviews, 189612
  - Allison, John, Date: 05-09-2006; 189665 (Disc 1)
    General note
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Fire station Subject 2: Northside; Disc Number: CDA-12, MP3-10; File Name: johnallison1_20060509
  - Allison, John, Date: 05-09-2006; 189664 (Disc 2)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Fire station; Subject 2: West end; Subject 3: Downtown; Subject 4: Northside; Disc Number: CDA-12, MP3-10; File Name: johnallison2_20060509
  - Alvarez, Abel, Date: 09-08-2006; 189663 (Disc 3)
    Interviewer: Rebecca Estrada; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Northeast; Disc Number: CDA-1, MP3-1; File Name: abelalvarez1_20060908
  - Angelos, Elizabeth, Date: 01-26-2007; 189662 (Disc 4)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Downtown; Subject 2: Greeks; Subject 3: School;s Subject 4: Transportation; Disc Number: CDA-11, MP3-6; File Name: elizabethangelos1_20070126
  - Angelos, Elizabeth, Date: 02-21-2007; 189661 (Disc 5)
    Interviewer: Laurie Feinswog; Subject 1: Downtown; Subject 2: Greeks; Subject 3: Schools; Subject 4: Transportation; Disc Number: CDA-11, MP3-6; File Name: elizabethangelosscanning_20070221.
  - Ashby, Lynn Cox, Date: 07-11-2006; 189660 (Disc 6)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Memorial; Subject 2: Politics; Subject 3: Transportation; Subject 4: Society; Disc Number: CDA-20, MP3-17; File Name: lynnashby1_20060711.
  - Bonilla, Johnny, Date: 07-20-2006; 189659 (Disc 7)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Entertainment; Subject 3: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-14, MP3-12; File Name: johnnybonilla1_20060720.
  - Bryant, Thelma, Date: 03-15-2007; 189658 (Disc 8)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Schools; Subject 2: Black Houston; Subject 3: Third Ward; Disc Number: CDA-30, MP3-25; File Name: thelmabryant1_20070315/.
  - Bryant, Thelma, Date: 03-15-2007; 189657 (Disc 9)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: Schools Subject 2: Black Houston Subject 3: Third Ward Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-30, MP3-25 File Name: thelmabryant2_20070315
  - Cooley, Dr. Denton A Date: 08-01-2007, 189656 (Disc 10)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Subject 2: Montrose; Subject 3: Schools; Subject 4: Med Center; Subject 5: Downtown; Disc Number: CDA-5, MP3-5; File Name: dentoncooley1_20060801.
  - Daleo, Lou., Date: 06-19-2007; 189655 (Disc 11)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: County Subject; 2: East end; Subject 3: Telephone; Subject 4: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-19, MP3-16; File Name: loudaleo1_20060619.
  - Daleo, Lou., Date: 06-19-2007; 189654 (Disc 12)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Southeast; Subject 3: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-19, MP3-16; File Name: loudaleo2_20060619.
  - Daleo, Lou., Date: 06-19-2007; 189653 (Disc 13)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Southeast; Subject 2: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-19, MP3-16; File Name: loudaleo3_20060619.
  - Daleo, Lou, Date: 06-19-2007; 189652 (Disc 14)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Transportation; Disc Number: CDA-19, MP3-16 File Name: loudaleo4_2006061.9.
  - Davis, Robert, Date: 06-19-2007; 189651 (Disc 15)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Disc Number: CDA-27, MP3-22; File Name: robertdavis1_20060829.
  - Davis, Robert, Date: 06-19-2007; 189650 (Disc 16)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Subject 2: Downtown; Disc Number: CDA-27, MP3-22; File Name: robertdavis2_20060829.
  - Davis, Robert File Name: robertdavis3_20060829 Date: 06-19-2007 Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Disc Number: CDA-27, MP3-22., 189649 (Disc 17)
  - Davis, Robert, Date: 06-19-2007; 189648 (Disc 18)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Disc Number: CDA-27, MP3-22; File Name: robertdavis4_20060829.
  - Davis, Robert, Date: 06-19-2007; 189647 (Disc 19)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Disc Number: CDA-27, MP3-22; File Name: robertdavis5_20060829.
  - Gantt, Ken, Date: 03-03-2007; 189646 (Disc 20)
    Interviewer: Laurie Feinswog/ Chris Daigle; Subject 1: 6th Ward; Subject 2: Houston drugs; Disc Number: CDA-17, MP3-14; File Name: kengantt1_20070303.
  - Hancock, Virginia, Date: 01-09-2007; 189645 (Disc 21)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Telephone; Subject 2: East end; Subject 3: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-31, MP3-26; File Name: virginiahancock1_20070109.
  - King, Lesta, Date: 01-25-2007; 189644 (Disc 22)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Heights; Subject 2: East end; Subject 3: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-18, MP3-15; File Name: lestaking1_20070125.
  - King, Lesta, Date: 01-25-2007; 189643 (Disc 23)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Schools; Subject 2: East end; Disc Number: CDA-18, MP3-15; File Name: lestaking2_20070125.
  - King, Lesta, Date: 01-25-2007; 189642 (Disc 24)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Spring Branch; Disc Number: CDA-18, MP3-15; File Name: lestaking3_20070125.
  - King, Lesta, Date: 01-25-2007; 189641 (Disc 25)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Transportation; Disc Number: CDA-18, MP3-15; File Name: lestaking4_20070125.
  - Malone, Ann, Date: 02-13-2007; 189640 (Disc 26)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Northeast; Subject 2: Schools; Subject 3: Nightlife; Subject 4: Downtown; Disc Number: CDA-2, MP3-2; File Name: annmalone1_20070213.
  - Marek, Ralph, Date: 08-29-2006; 189639 (Disc 27)
    Interviewer: Rebecca Estrada; Subject 1: Northside; Subject 2: Oak Forest; Disc Number: CDA-26, MP3-21; File Name: ralphmarek1_20060829.
  - Marek, Ralph, Date: 08-29-2006; 189638 (Disc 28)
    Interviewer: Rebecca Estrada; Disc Number: N/A; File Name: ralphmarek2_20060829.
  - McDowell, George, Date: 01-10-2007; 189637 (Disc 29)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Southwest; Disc Number: CDA-8, MP3-8; File Name: georgemcdowell1_20070110.
  - Metzler, John, Date: 12-12-2006; 189636 (Disc 30)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-13, MP3-11; File Name: johnmetzler1_20061212.
  - Metzler, John, Date: 12-12-2006; 189635 (Disc 31)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Recreation; Subject 3: Stores; Disc Number: CDA-13, MP3-11; File Name: johnmetzler2_20061212.
  - Moreno Family, Date: 09-12-2006; 189634 (Disc 32)
    Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Hispanics; Disc Number: CDA-22, MP3-19; File Name: morenofamily1_20060912..
  - Moreno Family, Date: 09-12-2006; 189633 (Disc 33)
    Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Subject 1: East end; Subject 2: Hispanics; Disc Number: CDA-23, MP3-19; File Name: morenofamily2_20060912.
  - Moreno Family, Date: 09-12-2006; 189632 (Disc 34)
    > Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Disc Number: CDA-24, MP3-19; File Name: morenofamily3_20060912.
  - Mousner, Della and James, Date: 09-18-2006; 189631 (Disc 35)
    Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Subject 1: Spring Branch; Disc Number: CDA-9, MP3-9; File Name: jamesanddellamousner1_20060918.
  - Mousner, Della and James, Date: 09-18-2006; 189630 (Disc 36)
    Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Disc Number: CDA-10, MP3-9; File Name: jamesanddellamousner1_20060918.
  - Pollard, Sr. Donna, Date: 09-05-2006; 189629 (Disc 37)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Garden Oaks; Subject 2: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-29, MP3-24; File Name: srdonnapollard1_20060905.
  - Roussel, Peter, Date: 09-19-2006; 189628 (Disc 38)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: West University; Subject 2: Sports; Subject 3: Schools; Disc Number: CDA-25, MP3-20; File Name: peterroussel1_20060919.
  - Schleyer, Robert, Date: 08-27-2006; 189627 (Disc 39)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: River Oaks; Subject 2: Schools; Subject 3: Montrose; Subject 4: Downtown; Disc Number: CDA-28, MP3-23; File Name: robertschleyer1_20060827.
  - Schleyer, Robert, Date: 08-27-2006; 189626 (Disc 40)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance; Subject 1: Buffs; Subject 2: Rodeo; Disc Number: CDA-28, MP3-23; File Name: robertschleyer2_20060827.
  - Simon, Esther, Date: 09-20-2006; 189625 (Disc 41)
    Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Subject 1: West end; Disc Number: CDA-6, MP3-7; File Name: esthersimon1_20060920.
  - Simon, Esther, Date: 09-20-2006; 189624 (Disc 42)
    Interviewer: Theresa Bujnoch; Subject 1: West end; Disc Number: CDA-7, MP3-7; File Name: esthersimon2_20060920.
  - Turner, John, Date: 02-13-2007; 189623 (Disc 43)
    Interviewer: Laurie Feinswog; Disc Number: CDA-15, MP3-13; File Name: JohnTurner1_20070213.
  - Turner, John Date: 02-13-2007, 189622 (Disc 44)
    Interviewer: Laurie Feinswog Subject 1: --- Subject 2: --- Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-16, MP3-13. File Name: JohnTurner2_20070213
  - Villalpando, Moises Date: 05-31-2006, 189621 (Disc 45)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: Northside Subject 2: East end Subject 3: Schools Subject 4: St. Joe's Hospital Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-21, MP3-18. File Name: moisesvillapando1_20060531
  - Weems, Carrington F. Date: 08-09-2006, 189620 (Disc 46)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: Slate only Subject 2: --- Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-4, MP3-4. File Name: carringtonweems1_20060809
  - Weems, Carrington F. Date: 08-09-2006 File Name: carringtonweems2_20060810, 189619 (Disc 47)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: River Oaks Subject 2: Downtown Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-4, MP3-4.
  - Weems, Carrington F. Date: 08-09-2006, 189618 (Disc 48)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: River Oaks Subject 2: Schools Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-4, MP3-4. File Name: carringtonweems3_20060811
  - Wignberg, Bethel Date: 01-18-2007, 189617 (Disc 49)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: East end Subject 2: Schools Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-3, MP3-3. File Name: bethelwignberg1_20070118
  - Wignberg, Bethel Date: 01-18-2007, 189616 (Disc 50)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: East end Subject 2: --- Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-3, MP3-3. File Name: bethelwignberg2_20070118
  - Wignberg, Bethel Date: 01-18-2007, 189615 (Disc 51)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: East end Subject 2: Recreation Subject 3: --- Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-3, MP3-3. File Name: bethelwignberg3_20070118
  - Williams, Margaret (Albert Leroy Nelson and Margot William) Date: 12-15-2006, 189614 (Disc 52)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: West end Subject 2: Schools Subject 3: Race Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-32, MP3-27. File Name: williamsandnelson1_20061215
  - Williams, Margaret (Albert Leroy Nelson and Margot William) Date: 12-15-2006, 189613 (Disc 53)
    Interviewer: Mike Vance Subject 1: West end Subject 2: Schools Subject 3: Race Subject 4: --- Subject 5: --- Disc Number: CDA-32, MP3-27. File Name: williamsandnelson2_20061215